I wonder
what that rain tastes like.
I used to love the rain
when I was a kid.
I used to sit out here
and watch the lightning storms.
That sounds beautiful.
Okay, so what do we got here?
What am I reaching for?
I'll reach wherever
the fuck I wanna reach, motherfucker.
I'm like some bad virus
you just can't shake.
Okay.
So, what do we got here?
Fuckin' stay out of my head!
You're welcome, kid.
So, what do we got here?
We reach out and reach out,
and flippin' and flippin' the switches
like a goddamn monkey
to see if something clicks. Huh.
Now, where I come from,
we call that a clue.
Where the hell have you been?
Fuck being fired, boss. I quit.
What the fuck was that?
Am I talking?
God. Can you hear me?
Yeah! I can hear you.
Thank Christ.
Well, I seem to be holding together
pretty good right now.
I... I call that a win.
Where the hell have you been?
I've been here
the whole time.
Why wouldn't you just talk to me?
It's not that easy.
- No hat?
- It's not my hat.
That hat belongs to the Investigator
that the protomolecule
keeps making out of my corpse
over and over and over again.
It couldn't kill me this time.
But we might not have long.
I... I brought my crew out here
because I thought we were helping you,
not the protomolecule
wearing a Miller suite.
The protomolecule's
been using us both, pal.
But being inside your head,
watching you give a shit,
you helped me,
gave me something
to build on, you know?
You helped me outsmart the jailer.
Welcome back.
So, what happens now?
I found something.
Not what it wanted me to find.
No. Something else.
See, I've been flicking switches.
I've been turning on
everything they left behind...
And almost killing everyone.
Eh, I didn't have much control
over that part, okay?
But it was important,
because I found a place
that my new bosses can't go.
Every time I reach out,
that part withers...
Dies.
If it shuts down
whatever's trapping us here,
that'd be a start.
This planet's already a corpse.
Let's go kill its ghost.
I wish I was down there.
Have we talked about the slugs
covered in neurotoxin,
and the ocular parasites?
Well,
there is no restarting the reactor,
so I got a decaying orbit
and a fiery death up here.
Don't act like you're special.
But if we're all gonna die
up here and down there,
I wish I was with you.
With a friend, I mean.
I do know what you mean.
Let me call you back.
But how can we be sure
this spot is some sort
of a magic bullet?
What are the odds it's just
another root stuck in the wall?
So,
there was a war here, right,
between the beings
that made the protomolecule
and something even worse.
I know. I've seen them.
Well, we won't know for sure
until we get there,
but this place, this dead spot,
may mean that the war
left something behind.
What?
Something like a billion-year-old
unexploded bomb?
Yeah, something like that.
See, this bomb, if it exists,
kills every bit
of protomolecule it touches.
And right now, that's what I need.
- And I wanna help you.
- Come on.
Everything I've done
over the last year
has been to help you,
even if it meant looking crazy
in front of everyone.
Well, I know it ain't been easy
lugging me around in your skull.
Well, we all owe you. I owe you.
But it's not just me.
I also need to get everyone away
from this place alive.
Help me save the ships first.
Then I'll do whatever you need.
You ever met anybody
you didn't wanna save?
Look, maybe this does both.
Bomb works, I'll use it to kill
all the protomolecule on the planet.
Your ships go free.
You're sure you can do that
without killing us all?
No.
But the other option is,
well, you watch everyone
starve to death while your ships burn,
and I get trapped here forever,
looking for something I'll never find.
So...
Bought ourselves a little time,
but not much.
We're scraping more atmosphere
than we calculated at this altitude.
How's the tether holding up?
More oscillation in the line
than I hoped.
I'm seeing increased drag, too.
Can we give the Barb another boost?
Yeah, we're gonna have to.
Hold on.
Barbapiccola, are you there?
Here.
We are picking up more drag
than expected.
We're going to do another burn.
Give us two minutes
to brace and make safe.
Copy that.
All hands prepare
for orbital correction.
How many more of these burns
can we afford?
Batteries will give us five, maybe.
Close off any unused compartments
and shut down air recycling to them.
That's not gonna buy us much.
Just do it.
And kill water recycling.
Thrusters don't like dirty water.
Well, let me know
if the tank gets that low.
All right.
You know...
If they dump their ore,
reduce their mass,
we could get it as high
as seven or eight.
We're not there yet.
Copy that.
The Rocinante has attached
what appears to be a towing system
to the Barbapiccola.
How much time is that giving them?
They just did another burn.
Orbital model says
they bought the Barb
another 20 hours at least.
How many of these burns
can the Roci do?
I don't know, but if they're
tethered, they're very vulnerable.
If you're gonna use that shuttle
and take them out...
Understood.
It's okay, little man.
You can sleep.
So, we go back to the surface?
Then what? We starve?
You wanna stay here with those...
I'll be right here
when you wake up, huh?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
One, two, three.
You doing all right?
Everything still looks
a little green, but yeah.
- You?
- Same.
So, that bullet's dodged.
The next problem's gonna be food.
Some of these people are gonna
starve to death before help comes.
Is there something you're telling me?
I'm just inviting you to come
camp with me. Our camp, not...
Does your boss know
that you're asking me to sleep over?
What is it with you two?
Is this some jealousy thing?
Because Murtry and I never...
I didn't ask, and I don't care.
He just reminds me of some of the guys
that I grew up with.
Well, you should give him a chance.
He's a pragmatist like you.
And he's good to his people.
Just because someone is good to you,
it doesn't mean
that you can trust them.
I do trust him.
And you guys don't like each other
because you're exactly fucking alike.
I'd never lie to you.
Fuck.
Oh, fuck.
You're tired?
I'm doing all the work here.
I've been awake
for three days straight.
So, yeah, I'm fucking tired.
Yeah, you and me both.
And thin.
It's like every time they rip me apart
and paste me back together again,
there's a little less of me
to work with.
Jesus.
One foot in front of the other
until we make it,
or we die trying, hmm?
That's a hell of a pep talk.
You ready, or...
All right, now,
don't walk off that edge
till I get the thing turned on, okay?
Uh-huh.
Ah, okay.
You want me to climb down there?
Climb. Jump. Whatever.
Just get in the hole.
Go on. It won't hurt you.
Where does this go?
Closer to our bomb.
And it's faster than walking.
- So just, you know, jump in the hole.
- Holden.
You're not going in that, are you?
What are you doing here?
I heard you talking to no one.
That was him, right? Your ghost?
He's not a ghost,
but yes, that was Miller.
You were talking
about saving the ships.
Can he do that?
Maybe.
- I'll go with you.
- No.
- I can help.
- No, you can't.
My ship is going to burn, too.
My people are going to die,
same as yours.
I have just as much to lose.
I can't see him when anyone's around,
and I need him to guide me.
Guide you to what?
If what I'm doing actually works,
everyone will know soon.
Report on the Belter camp?
They're not hungry enough yet
to be a threat. Why?
Situation in orbit has changed.
We're gonna need
to take action down here, and soon.
They don't maintain a perimeter
or an armed watch
unless you count Amos.
Do you?
I'm gonna need location
on Amos and Holden now.
Everyone check in.
We need eyes on Holden.
Copy that.
Dr. Okoye,
I'm gonna need all RCE personnel
to stay within our camp.
What? Why?
For your safety.
No one has eyes on Holden.
You were rather friendly with him.
You wouldn't have any idea
where he might be, do you?
I don't know where he is right now.
This is very important.
I need to know
where Captain Holden has gone.
And if you know anything about that,
you're going to tell me.
Right now.
Light shuttle two
is cleared for launch.
Why are we launching a shuttle?
Missed what happened to the last one?
Security division's authority.
To do what? Get our last shuttle
ripped to shreds?
We still have people
who will someday want a ride.
- Chief Murtry's orders.
- Why would he even...
If you don't already know,
it's not your business.
Now, sit the fuck down and go back
to doing whatever it is you do.
Okay.
No problem.
- Okoye here.
- Hey, give me that.
I need to take this call.
Murtry says no communications.
Hey, Doc, you seen Wei?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. No one's allowed
to talk to her, all right?
I wouldn't.
All right. What the fuck's going on?
Holden went with Miller.
Murtry and Wei went after him.
I think he's in trouble.
Is there something
we still need to do?
Shit.
Amos.
Can you get a fix
on the captain?
I'm not getting a signal.
Okay, if he checks in,
tell him I'm coming,
and that he should watch his back.
- Is something going on down there?
- Yup.
- Anything I can do?
- No.
All right, show me where Holden went.
Wei, I'm coming for your boss.
Don't be there when I do.
Wake up, Sleeping Beauty.
Miller!
Where the fuck are you? What do I do?
Nice nap?
Man, play with the toys later.
- What now?
- We take a walk.
All this shit's left over
from when the planet died.
Yeah, everything they left behind.
This shit just keeps following you
around, don't it, kid?
Come on.
Stay out of my head, assholes!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
It's just my former masters
cracking the whip,
wondering why I don't jump.
Yeah, they're looking
for a way back in.
Is there anything I can do?
Yeah.
Why don't we try
killing 'em off for good,
see how that works?
- You're going to follow them.
- I am.
I'm going with you.
Don't try to stop me.
You don't need my permission.
But it might be a one-way trip, Doc.
We are already on one.
The cable's too elastic.
It's stretching under the stress.
I can take up the slack here.
No.
Better if I put some tension
on the cable from this end.
No more than a quarter turn.
More might snap it.
Okay.
Here goes.
Shit.
Hmm.
Why text?
No, I did not.
What the hell is he up to now?
Thanks for the heads-up.
Edward Israel light shuttle,
this is the Rocinante.
Appears you're on
a potential collision course.
Please respond immediately.
Edward Israel,
this is Alex Kamal of the Rocinante.
This is the Edward Israel.
- Go ahead.
- Yeah.
Any reason why your shuttle
is heading towards us?
Stand by, Rocinante.
Checking on that.
Yeah, I'm gonna be needing
an answer to that right now.
- Naomi?
- What's wrong?
I think we might be under attack.
- From what?
- Brace for impact.
Lucia, brace!
RCE shuttle, pull off.
Change course immediately,
or I will fire.
Look out, guys!
We've got debris incoming!
Lucia!
Naomi.
What the hell's going on
out there?
- Naomi!
- I'm coming!
Naomi, come in!
Alex,
there's nothing you can do.
Stay off this channel,
and do not spin the ship.
Copy that.
That's it. Don't panic.
- I'm coming.
- Okay.
- I'm right here.
- Help, Naomi!
Stay calm.
- Yes, it's okay.
- I can't breathe. I can't...
I'm just a few seconds
behind you, okay?
- I can't...
- Just breathe.
I'm coming!
Naomi!
Stay calm.
Just keep breathing, okay?
I'm just a couple seconds away.
I'm right behind you.
Okay, reach out your hand to me.
Reach as far as you can.
I'm trying. I'm trying.
- Stay with me, Lucia.
- I can't... I can't...
- Reach out!
- I can't see you!
I can't see you. Please.
Please. Where are you?
Fashaam!
I got you!
Hold on to me!
It's okay.
I'm here. I'm here.
I'm here. You're okay.
It's okay.
I've got you now.
I've got you.
It's okay now. We're okay.
Thank you.
Clear.
- Where'd Holden go from here?
- We need a fix.
Can't reach the ship.
Wait.
- What is it?
- I've got a message from Amos.
Wei, I'm coming for your boss.
Don't be there when I do.
Your boyfriend
has an economical way with words.
I'd rather not go
into unknown territory
with an armed killer at my back.
Which means we take him here.
If it has to be done, I do it.
That's the deal.
You have my word.
Now comes the hard part.
- Which is?
- Actually finding this bomb.
I thought you knew
where this dead spot was.
I know
where the corpse is buried.
We might just have to do
a little digging
to find the bullet inside, you know?
Through here.
You all right?
Across that, I take it?
Oh, yeah.
If I slip off, how long will I fall?
Mm...
Rest of your life.
Watch your step.
Bitch, I see one more
goddamn thing come out of your ship,
I will blow you into scrap.
Assholes. How bad are we hit?
It ain't good.
We lost 11 thrusters.
I burned a ton of power
firing the PDCs
and a bunch of reaction mass
trying to control this spin.
The batteries are low,
but I don't see any extra draw.
No shorts draining power.
Can you kill the rest of this spin?
I'll have to keep
rolling the ship,
but this damn tether's
making it tricky.
- Oh!
- What was that?
The Barb must be catching
some more drag.
That tether's pulling us back.
Much more of this and it will snap.
I really need to do another burn,
or this is gonna get worse fast.
How many of the aft thrusters
are gone?
Everything on that side is dead.
So, if I burn, we start to spin,
and I gotta roll the ship
in order to stop it.
There has to be a way.
Bloody RCE sons of bitches.
If they have anything else
to throw at us, we're sitting ducks.
You were bluffing about your weapons?
We don't have enough juice to spare
to fire the PDCs.
We have to let it go.
The crew from the Barbapiccola
can transit over to us.
- Cut the tether.
- No...
Let the ship go.
Lucia.
No one else dies for this dream.
We tried everything.
No.
No, we did not.
Alex.
Railgun's got
its own batteries.
It's not gonna drain main power
if we fire it.
It isn't about power.
- It's about snapping that tether.
- I don't understand.
Without the drive to compensate,
the kick from the railgun
turns it into a big ol' thruster.
And it won't throw us into a spin
in the wrong direction.
It isn't a gentle push.
It'll feel like falling off a cliff.
I don't know if the cable can take it.
If it don't work, we'll evacuate
the Barb like Lucia said.
But at this point,
we got nothing to lose.
Okay.
I'm gonna go below and see if I can
fix any of those bad thrusters.
- Warn me before you fire.
- You got it.
Tell Felcia what we're doing.
All I know for sure
is that this room
is the center of the dead spot.
So, just look around for anything
that seems out of place.
I think I got it.
Don't keep it to yourself.
What's it look like?
The eye of an angry god.
I need to put myself
into something physical.
You can do that?
How do you think I've been
turning all this shit on?
Well, once I'm inside,
I'm gonna flip every last switch on
in the network, okay?
I'm gonna connect myself
to everything.
I'm gonna wake up
the whole damn planet.
- So, be ready.
- And then what?
You walk into that?
Boom.
You came here to die.
If you can call this livin', pal.
But, hey, I'm gonna take the rest
of this place with me, too.
And...
maybe 100,000 screaming souls
finally get some rest.
So, yeah, I...
Ah! Damn it!
We need to talk about that ride, kid.
Next clue in the case.
Ah! Fuck!
Man.
They really don't want me doing this.
I don't have a lot of time.
Okay.
That.
That's mostly intact, and it's mobile.
All right, when I take control of it,
I need you to guide me as close
to this angry god's eye thing
as you can get
without me touching it, okay?
If I go inside without taking
everything else with me, we lose.
How will I know when you've connected
to the rest of the planet?
You'll know.
And that'll fix the ships?
Here's hoping.
This is really the end, isn't it?
It is for me.
But, hey, I'm hoping
you make it out okay.
Oh, uh, there's a glob of blue shit
under the decking of the cargo bay.
Uh, you might wanna
clean that up, after.
Fuck. Of course.
Yeah.
This thing...
killed the Builders,
and now we're using their Ring Gates.
Yeah.
Yeah, that could be a problem.
You might wanna look into that.
That's it?
No explanation?
No cop stories or tortured metaphors?
Hey, I got you this far, kid.
Rest is up to you.
Water.
Rain is just water.
Doesn't really taste like anything.
Hey.
Amos.
Where's Holden?
Murtry's dealing with him.
Cut the tough-guy shit.
We both know what we are.
We're survivors.
We roll with the punches.
No one does what we do
and keeps their hands clean.
We kill people for money.
And it's always someone else
getting rich from our work,
but this time, it can be us.
Don't do this.
Just fucking talk to me.
I don't wanna hurt you.
And we both know
that you don't wanna hurt me.
One fucked-up day of shitty choices
for us both, but afterward,
we can walk away
from this life forever.
Is that the story
that Murtry sold you?
That's how it is.
I told you that I would
never lie to you.
I remember.
I'm going after Holden.
And if you're in my way,
I'm going through you.
I can't let you do that.
Go!
Holden!
Holden?
Everyone is braced.
We're ready.
Oof.
That gave us a little boost.
Not enough to stabilize us for long,
but I can get a few more shots off
before the power runs out.
I've got two thrusters back.
It might buy enough time
for me to make this work.
- Keep it up.
- If it doesn't work...
If we gotta get your people
off that ship, we will.
Miller!
Are you there?
Can you hear me?
Holden!
Doc?
Holden! Holden!
What are you doing here?
Are you hurt?
No, but Murtry's coming to kill you.
He shot Amos.
Is he dead?
I don't know.
Wei is dead. Amos killed her.
Miller!
What is that?
Do not touch that.
Just wait here.
I'll be right back.
Whoa. Fuck.
Who the fuck... are you?
Who the fuck are you?
Hey!
Hello?
Uh, I'm Elvi...
Okoye.
Who...
What are you?
Fucked, lady.
What I am is fucked.
Where the hell's Holden?
I think he went to find Amos.
Well,
his timing fuckin' sucks.
Wait. You are Holden's ghost.
Miller?
Yeah.
Yeah, I've looked better.
How are you able to talk to me?
It's complicated.
Now, listen.
You see something funny
in this room somewhere?
Somethin' unusual?
Yes, that field effect.
I can see it. What is it?
With any luck, the off switch
for the whole fucking planet.
How'd that happen?
Well, then.
That was a little trickier
than I thought.
Okay, then.
Okay.
Lady.
You're gonna help me.
Where's Amos?
Is he alive?
I don't know.
He was too hurt to walk,
and he had a shotgun.
Going around him
seemed the wiser choice.
If he's dead, so are you.
Wei tried to appeal to his humanity,
but he killed her for it.
You should start appealing to mine.
You broken my planet yet?
Working on it.
You are really Detective Miller
from Ceres,
sentient and independent?
Well, if I'm not,
I'm acing my Turing test.
About how far am I from this thing?
A few meters, roughly.
Move me a little closer.
I don't know how fast
these locals are gonna react
when they figure out what I'm doing.
The locals?
Let's just hope you don't meet.
You're about a meter away.
Is this good?
Okay. Yeah.
People like you always forget.
Civilization has a lag time,
like light delay.
You come out here,
and you think
because you're civilized,
civilization comes with you.
Throw your gun down.
Put your hands on your head.
You'll only get this one chance.
We're all just walking
in the footsteps of history,
the ancient frontier.
All those post offices
and railroads and jails
cost thousands of lives to build.
And this is no different.
I am the kind of man
the frontier needs.
You're the kind that comes
after my work is done.
You should've stayed at home
until I built a post office.
I met another guy once
who liked using past genocides
to justify his bullshit.
You weren't persuaded?
A friend of mine shot him in the face.
You won't even have the balls
to finish me, will you, boy?
You are finished.
I'm gonna bring you back
to stand trial,
then drop you in a cell forever.
We call that "civilization."
All right, aim me.
Come on. Point me at this thing.
Just, uh, go straight ahead.
No!
Get off!
Man, that could've gone better.
Well, I'll guide you back.
Nah. I'm fucked. I can't move.
Got it. That's it.
Good. Good.
Uh, let's go. Let's go.
Wait!